We just went through the discovery process, qualifying,
making sure that we want to move forward
with the analysis proposal
because this is the most work, biggest part of this process.
I'm gonna show it to you everything through it.
So let's go ahead and dive in.
But real quick, let's go back into the process flow again,
just to make sure that we're on the
same page about where we are.
So lead comes in, we have the discovery call.
They are qualified, right?
We said yes, they've requested a proposal.
We are gonna build the analysis.
So again, I have somebody internally, her name is Annette.
She is the one who builds all these analysis for me
because it's a lot of work that
allows me to handle the sales.
'cause it's really hard to run an agency sales process if
you're doing calls and building it,
unless you are full-time sales and doing nothing else.
That means every day you wake up, you,
you breathe sleep sales, that's usually
for a dedicated sales rep.
A lot of you don't have one
and a lot of us are don't really need one.
And you can do it yourselves, but you need that person
to do this 'cause I'm gonna walk you through it.
I'm gonna show you how much it is. So
after we have this built, we get into the analysis call,
which is just a review of the deck.
So I'm not even gonna use the slides on this.
I'm just gonna dive over to the proposals,
the analysis and show you what it looks like.
So this is one that we literally just sent out this week.
This is the most up-to-date one.
You're gonna get access to this but view only. Okay?
Because I can't tell you guys
how much times in the wild I see the exact things
that I give people in this program.
And it like it is immensely frustrating when it's like you
don't even change the fonts and the colors.
You just take exactly what it is.
It makes you look really bad. Just trust me.
So I'm giving you this as an example to show you
what an end result looks like.
I'm begging you to please not just rip this.
Like if you're watching this recorded
or live, please don't just rip this exactly for word,
for word for it is take it and make it your own.
Please. These are yours to use to own.
But like, you know, just be mindful
that if you're sending this out to people,
you're only hurting yourself because they see this.
So that being said, what we did is we made a
very stripped down version.
This is your template, okay?
Your logo here, you know, this is blueprint branded stuff.
It's the exact same thing. Slide for slide.
But this is what you're gonna get access to, right?
So I'm showing you this as an example,
but I am giving you this as the editing.
Are we clear there? Sorry to be condescending in that sense,
but I just have to say that
because like, it's wild how much like exact word
for word stuff we see out there
and it like, I'm only trying to help y'all out.
It doesn't, it doesn't help out your case.
So that means go through this
and you're gonna need to customize it.
You're gonna need to spend some time for homework going
through this and saying, okay, we don't maybe have this part
so we'll change this or we'll add this here.
But either way, this is a proven analysis
and proposal template.
It crushes it by far and away the highest
and the most positive feedback
that we get from prospects too.
They love it. There's a lot of value in this.
I slant this very heavily saying this is
what agencies charge for this
work we're doing for you for free.
So we can properly scope out your campaign.
Okay, so the first couple slides here, I'd like
to put in screenshots, case studies.
I use Arus because it's allows me
to compare apples to apples.
You can use search console, Google Analytics,
if you got phone call data, conversion data,
That's always the best.
But the reason why I like it for this is
because as we get into this
and we analyze their performance,
we're showing them arus stuff
so they can compare themselves head
to head versus case studies, right?
So it's context. So we took a screenshot
and we just put in this little thing here that says,
this is when we started you SEMrush, whatever you want.
But because we're using a trusts throughout this proposal,
it makes sense, right?
For them to see, okay, you know, this is a similar law firm
doing what we do the same
practice area but in a different market.
I can see their traffic
and I can see the value of their traffic tool.
Always walk them through the traffic value here
so they can see, you know, the value
of the service that we're providing.
So put in as many as you have.
If you only have one, use one, I have four in here just
so I can kind of relate them.
These are some personal injuries, some criminal offense.
I'll kind of pick and choose the one of them to talk to
and kind of walk them through really quickly.
But I think it's very powerful
to start off these presentations with results, right?
With real results, it usually gets their attention.
So again, I'm gonna be flipping back
and forth just so you can see
what the clean version looks like
versus like the template version.
So the next piece
that we get into is the performance scorecard.
This is, this is important, you know,
this is not a traditional proposal.
A proposal is really, this is
what you get in when this is an analysis by saying
we're analyzing your performance
and we do so in five different buckets.
So I'm talking you through how to pitch this
and talk people through it too.
How I'm talking you through it is exactly
how I talk prospects through it.
And we will also include recorded calls
of me giving these from out in the wild.
So you can see, you know, what these look like in real time,
but I'm, again, I'm just walking you through this stuff.
So there's five different areas here.
We used to have a score here associated with it,
but I took it out because it was completely outta context
and it usually ended up asking more questions
and detracting from the main purpose.
We used to have like a a score out of 100
that we would score them on, but it just created confusion.
So I removed it, but it's still, it's still a scorecard
analysis because we're analyzing each of these.
So I like to tell 'em, look, the first thing
that we're gonna look at is your current SEO performance.
We're gonna look at Google search, AI search,
and Google Mouse pack, right?
We're gonna benchmark you and show you where you are
and we're gonna throw in some competitor data there too.
Then we're getting into the four key components of SEO,
which is essentially how we scope campaigns.
I call 'em the four pillars.
Local website performance, a k,
a technical foundational work, content performance,
and then links press, a k, a,
you know, link building, right?
So if y'all are long-term blueprint members here,
these are the four pillars that I used
to talk about or the three pillars.
Now four pillars were local that used
to talk about years ago, still holds true in SEO
and then there's just some write-ups here that kind
of explained to them what it is.
And then the first thing that we do is we get
into the search performance, right?
So again, slide for slide, same thing.
You can see ours are designed a little bit better just
to give you some inspiration here if you will.
Now, this first slide here,
it looks at their law firm or their website.
And I like to take Anette, take a screenshot
of the top search bar in Arus
and then the traffic on here as well
so they can see trending.
But I'll really walk them through
and I know these screenshots are hard to see,
but you know what you're looking at here.
Lemme see if this one's a little bit cleaner. It's not.
What I'll walk them through here is their current
traffic amount, right?
Is what I'll, I'll focus on
and I'll explain to them, Hey look,
this is not apples to apples.
If you open up Google Analytics,
it's not gonna say this exact number, but it's relevant
because now we can compare you to our case studies
and we can also compare you to competitors.
So you can see how you stack up.
So I just kind of like erode the fact
that this data isn't the most accurate in a sense,
but it's comparison data, right?
It's it's top level analysis data.
But really what I'll drive into is the value of the traffic.
So that says 33,000.
She also writes it up here so they can read it.
And the reason why I drive into this, this is important
because that number to me is the most important KPI
and what we're doing here.
Meaning if they have a ton of organic traffic,
if they've got a hundred thousand visits a month,
but their organic traffic value is a thousand, it tells you
that the keywords that they're ranked
for don't really have any value.
And I like to pitch them.
Again, something that I also wanna drive home throughout
this process is that like we are looking for opportunities.
We were talking about boxing to throw jabs, right?
Move your head, Bob, blah, bob, jab, jab, jab.
These little jabs are little pitches.
We're starting to plant little seeds in their head
for a pitch, which is a story
that we're telling them, right?
And every single one is gonna be different.
So what's important here is this is a template.
We use this exact same template over
and over and over again.
But the nuances are in how I pitch this information, right?
Because Annette is an SEO specialist,
she's not a sales specialist, she's not looking
for stories and patterns.
She's looking for data. So I can analyze it
and tell the story that I want to tell.
And this is a great example. I think I have two open here.
This is another one that we just did.
So here's a good example kind of head to head up too.
This one here is not, well, they have a good amount
of traffic value, but just ignore that for a second, right?
Let let, let's say that we see
that they're like trending downwards here
and this one is clearly trending up
and they're doing well, right?
Like two very different pitches of the stories.
How do we pitch someone who's going up versus someone?
People going down are pretty easy to pitch.
It's you're losing traffic, we can fix that.
Versus, oh wow, they're increasing traffic
and their traffic value is good.
These are little data points that we're looking for to tell
that story and tell that pitch.
So even though their traffic is going up here,
I know from experience that this number is still,
it's a decent number, but it's still low
in the personal injury space.
If you're really humming, this should be a hundred thousand,
500,000, sometimes even over a
million dollars in traffic value.
That's how expensive these keywords are.
So I'm looking at this
and I'm also instructing Annette to say the next slide,
when we're finding competitors here, I tell her
to always make sure that she's finding competitors
that have a higher traffic value.
That's critical here. Why?
Because they might look at this
and be like, oh s**t, we're, we're doing great.
We don't need you. And I'll be like, hold, hold not so fast.
Yes, you're going up,
but when we benchmark you against the
market, you're getting crushed.
They're eating your lunch. It's not just about the traffic
going up and to the right, it's about
understanding what's out there.
The total potential, right?
Opportunity, jab, traffic value, jab, right?
So I'm looking for these different stories,
these different pockets to start seeding right away.
And I'm not proposing anything,
I'm just planting these seeds in their head
so they see it for themselves, right?
It's very important. It's very powerful stuff.
This is how agency sales is done.
I'm a consultant, I'm showing them data,
I'm helping 'em understand what's going on.
I'm consulting them throughout
this process and building trust.
But I'm also, again, planting those seeds in their head.
I'm starting to throw those jabs for that pitch.
Because when I propose $10,000 a month to them, 5,000,
whatever it comes to, if they're like, I don't know,
that seems like a lot because I'm going
up, they're gonna have that.
My voice in the back of their head being like, yeah,
but like we're, yeah, we're going up.
But like we are still only 10% of what our competitor is.
They are crushing us, right? So again, find what you have.
You cannot lie. You cannot lie is not maybe not the right
word, but you can't really manipulate the data
and the information because it just kind of is what it is.
That's why this is so good. But it is your job to analyze
that in the right way so you can ultimately land a pitch
that works even if they're crushing it, right?
Again, if they're, if they're not doing well, that's,
it's easy to pitch that if
track's going down, we can fix that.
But if it's going up, we still wanna look
for other competitors who are crushing it
because that's gonna help tell the story of,
dude, yeah, you're doing great.
And I, what I'll say to
'em too is I'll be like, this is awesome.
I love seeing this because this is momentum.
This means that the results are gonna happen faster for you
because you've already got a good baseline,
but you are still so far off from even
scratching the surface of your market.
There's so much meat left on the bone, you're doing
so well now as a business, imagine if you 10 x that, like
what would that do to your paid search bill, right?
How much are you paying on paid search per month?
Well, they're not paying anything. But again,
and it says that nature trust.
That's how I know that, again,
these are all different stories
or angles that we can use as we're telling the story.
So what a net will do is you'll find just two competitors
basically by just Googling their main keyword.
And again, just kind of trial
and erroring different high powered websites
to find the most powerful ones.
This is always to show them, I mean, attorneys love,
it's like an ego thing for them.
They love seeing how they're doing against competitors.
And I'll also have hres open on the call
and I'll be like, is there anyone
else you want to take a look at here?
Live on the call? And they'll always gimme
like a couple, we'll take a look at it.
Just again, build a rapport building conversation,
being an open book of information's, trying
to help them understand what's going
on with their business, right?
Makes sense. Cool. So next we get into local performance.
We use local Falcon for this.
So she just puts it in for every location that they have.
And then she'll do the main keyword.
So personal injury, lawyer, car
and lawyer, divorce, lawyer, whatever it is
that they wanna rank for, their main keyword.
She'll put that in for every location that they have.
She'll put the location down here
and then a screenshot of this.
Again, I see this
and I'm like, okay, they're doing pretty well, right?
So let's again, let's say
that these are all, they have five locations.
Let's say that they're all green, all green.
How do I pitch that? Right?
Their traffic's going up, they're all green.
I say, this is awesome.
What this tells me is that you gotta golden,
you got a Midas golden touch.
Every location that you have, you're shooting up
to the top of the rankings.
If you check your Google business profile,
you're probably getting 50 to a hundred phone calls on each.
This maybe not in Canton, Canfield, Ohio.
But point is is that then I'll start to see that pitch
of new office locations for them opening up new spaces
for them, helping them do that, walk that process
and adding value, adding value, adding value.
Right? Now of course they have some markets here
that aren't, I mean they're doing pretty well across the
board, but like Akron would be like, look, let's start here.
Let's punch this up and then once this is punched up,
we're gonna help you open up new applications across the
state for just a couple hundred bucks a month.
Because every, imagine the ROI in that,
let's say it's $500 a month for a new office lease,
but you're gonna get 50 phone calls a month.
If you pay Google ads for 50 phone calls a month,
you're talking about a hundred thousand dollars, right?
Dollars. The ROI in that is insane.
So I'm already starting to seed these things here.
A lot of the times, like this is a 40 slide deck.
You don't even have to get through the full analysis portion
until you've kind of like already got their attention
because you can feel this too, right?
Like we're talking about them, we're talking
about them, we're talking about them.
Even the case studies here are to say,
this is a website just like yours.
They were in a similar position, they were losing traffic
or you know, they had churn through a bad agency
or they are a criminal defense firm
who wanted to do personal injury.
Whatever it is. I'm telling the story to match to
where they are, to just, again, make it about them,
make it about them, make it about them.
And then we're talking about them, we're comparing them,
we're showing 'em how they're doing.
A lot of the times their current
agency isn't even doing this.
So they are like, oh wow, this is helpful information.
Thank you. We've also started throwing
in AI search stuff, right?
This is important. So this law firm's crushing it.
Uh, we actually, they didn't even wanna move forward
with a full presentation with us
because they have an agency who's obviously doing pretty
well for them, but that's why I'm showing this to you.
But basically what I'll tell 'em, I'm like, look,
like there's no denying the power of chat GPT, it's a part
of our process 'cause it falls under the umbrella
of search optimization.
But there's no real way to track it right now,
aside from visits in Google Analytics
and then also manual searching.
So this, all you have to do is just manually search
for them, you know, whatever their keyword is,
take a screenshot and put it in.
It's not an exact science by any means guys.
It's just a conversation starter
and it's a means to start selling your services, right?
Okay, so then we get into the website
optimization portion here.
Again, I'm gonna go back to your deck here
so you can see all this stuff is laid off for you.
Just gotta again, rebrand it, got the little, your logo here
as a reminder, a copy,
rebrand it, have a designer do it, whatever.
But now we move into the website optimization portion.
So this is when I start to tell them, I say, okay,
now we've looked at your performance.
Now we're gonna start talking about four pillars of search.
We're actually gonna do a high level audit here.
Now, if you become a client, we're gonna do a much deeper
audit and we're gonna fix everything for you too.
This is purely just to give you some context
of understanding and help us understand what the scope
of work will be when we're talking about website management
and technical SEO.
So we have this chart here. It is a very simple pass fail.
There's only 15, 16 things on here
that are just very high level stuff.
How do you fill this out? Well,
we got a spreadsheet for you.
So all you have to do is look to see where the tool is here.
And again, it's, it's mapped to the section of,
so current performance tech,
gloss SE optimization, this is it right here.
So target page index, all you have
to do is crawl their website using Screaming Frog.
And if you use something else too,
you can replace it with something else.
But Screaming Frog is free.
The 500 URLs I really like Screaming Frog.
It's what Annette uses. And then it's very simply
a pass fail, right?
And some of this is not an exact science, it's not exact.
This is purely 15 minute litmus test audit.
You don't need to spend too much time here.
It's just, I mean it's for you too.
It's, it's information that's valuable for for them.
But it's also good, good for you
because if you're like, holy crap,
they need an entirely new website, then you're probably need
to figure that out and pitch that to them, right?
And again, you see here all the stuff,
page speed insights, it's very simple.
Pass fail improvements needed.
And how do you decide pass fail versus improvements needed?
Figure it out. Y'all are the judge.
I don't have an exact metric for that.
This is no by no means A
and I can hide, I'll hide this for you right here too
and un hide it afterwards as a cleaner.
'cause we don't do the scores anymore.
But again, everything
that you need is here in this audit tab to go
through a lot of this process.
And I'll go through these other tabs in here as well.
So a lot of you have asked
before you've seen like, oh, how do you fill this out?
Where are you getting this information from?
Is Annette going through and filling out the spreadsheet?
And then once it's done, you literally just copy
and paste it into here.
You know, literally just
paste over this and it's right there.
You can link the spreadsheet too if you want.
I'm not that technically savvy anymore to figure that out.
But that's the website audit.
And then we'll just put like a very small summary here.
You know, a screenshot I like to, I for,
again, know who you're pitching, right?
Know your audience. We're talking to attorneys who, like,
when I start talking about tech messaging,
like they look at this and like,
what the FI don't know what this s**t is, dude.
Like I, I don't have time for this.
I, I literally go over this in 30 seconds.
I'm like, we're gonna send this to you. You can take a look
at it, send to your tech team if you want.
But I wanna focus on a few things here
that like are gonna ring a bell.
And that's usually spa page
speed can always use improvement.
And things like, like target pages, index title tags.
I'm like, this is old school on page SEO.
So again, thinking about these things, a lot
of these things are gonna fail, pass improvements needed.
Even if they're doing well, you can say, look, you're doing
so well and imagine if we fix this stuff
because you're gonna do even better, right?
And your current agency or whoever is missing these things.
We picked it up in 15 minutes.
Imagine what we could do with 15 hours.
You know, so again, jab looking for an opening,
bam punch in the face, hit 'em in the chin, right?
I'm just constantly jabbing at them
and it's not coming off as a pitch
because I'm just looking at the data
and I'm presenting to them facts.
They can't argue with this, right?
About the page speed here.
'cause they can see this, it's very clear fail
and they, they contextualize,
I understand my website's not fast enough.
It's not doing very well, right?
Alright, so then we move on to the local performance.
Again, you can see here same thing,
the local performance part here.
How do you fill it out? Well, we got a tab
for it right here under a local SEO.
So this is gonna tell you how it's done.
Local falcon's done for a lot of this.
But a, a good old fashioned Google business profile research
also does, you know, does wonders.
10 minutes spent here dumping a local falcon.
Go to the group's profile, look at the number of reviews,
how they're responding to them, average number
of stars, all these different things.
Again, how do you decide pass fail.
Y'all are smarter than me on a lot of this stuff.
You can figure it out. And then you're just
gonna dump it in here.
And I believe she has the GBP tab here, right?
Where she's got a business name versus two competitors
that are ranking in the top three total reviews,
average rating, and just a very simple
checklist of category.
Open 24 hours. Again, this is
by no means an exhaustive audit.
It is not supposed to be
because you don't wanna spend too much time on this.
These are purely things that we've built over time
that are like, what can they comprehend and understand
and visualize and see
and un help 'em understand that there's a gap
and there's room for improvement.
And room for improvement is
where the pitch comes into play, right?
We're looking at ways that we can make them more
money. So again, this
Person has multiple business profiles, so they just,
she did it for every business profile,
but if there's one, you just use one, right?
I'm actually gonna unshare this because,
'cause I sent this and they declined it.
I don't want their current agency to look at this.
What they probably did anyways, thinking here.
And then this slide is just a, a very simple summary, right?
Screenshot of the profile review strength.
You know, you can use chat GPT to write this stuff guys,
honestly, you can just paste,
you can download this spreadsheet, feed it to chat GPT
and say, gimme three bullet points on it.
Very simple stuff on doing that.
And then you've got these same slides here, right?
Very, very, very, very simple.
This is actually a different firm, you know,
but you can see it's very similar.
Then we move into content performance, right?
So this is where I start to talk more
because content is a big part
of the scope of work, obviously.
Well, let me get this thing outta the bottom here.
And, uh, it makes up a good chunk of ultimately
what it ends up costing them, right?
So this is the top pages report from arus.
I'm just gonna show you how to pull this up.
If you, if you don't know, this is one
of my favorite reports.
I don't really check these tools that much.
'cause honestly, I don't find 'em, ironically,
I don't find 'em to be that accurate.
But let's say I'm auditing the blueprint training here.
You know, this tool is amazing, don't get me wrong.
I just don't find it accurate in terms
of the traffic results.
But that's a different story, right?
And this is the top page report. Why I love this.
And I, so what I'll do
with these prospects too is I'll show them this
and then I say, let's just jump on over to AF
so we can look in real time.
'cause they'll always have questions like, oh,
can you show me this and this and this?
But like, generally speaking,
I'll just tell you what I'm usually looking at.
And 'cause Annette will just, she provides me the data.
It is what it is. And I, it's up to me to analyze this.
I will look at it. Couple of things.
One, I will look at share of traffic, right?
Like this is bad, right?
For blueprint, we don't do SEO here
for ourselves ironically,
but like 57% of traffic to the website coming
through one blog post red flag, right?
You don't wanna see that type of share
of voice dip distributor across content,
especially a blog post if it was like the homepage
or like a a service page maybe,
but even still, like, that's way too high.
So again, that would be something that I'm looking at
to pitch, to poke holes in their current content strategy.
The other biggest thing, honestly,
looking at the distribution of
what type of pages are ranking.
So with attorneys and law firms
and local businesses, you always want their top 10 pages
to be service pages, practice server pages, product pages.
It's where the money's made in
this, in these businesses, right?
Like they have to have bottom funnel pages ranking
or, you know, their,
their SEO is is basically just is
doing nothing for them, right?
So that's the other big thing is a lot
of times you'll see a ton of blog posts ranking,
and I'll tell them, that's when I'll start
to pitch our bottom up content strategy, right?
Where we focus on practice area pages first,
blog content second, blah, blah, blah.
That whole kind of spiel and pitch
and how those generate money.
Then just looking at the keywords that they're ranked for,
the volume, the position changes.
This is a whole, this, this report is amazing, right?
This is everything that you need to do, kind
of like a content analysis for,
for the scope of what we're talking about here.
So I'll talk to them through that.
And again, I'm just looking at this poking at holes,
you know, like your blog, like they have the,
you can't really see it here, but their number one
page here rank, it's a blog post.
It's 40% of traffic.
I would've been like, yo, this is a problem, it's a problem.
I let, if you pull open your analytics, I guarantee
that you're getting zero phone calls from this
and we want to change that, right?
So then we start getting into a little bit more details here
on location, page performance, right?
So what she does here is she's just basically
pulling HRES data.
She's searching by location up here.
So like whatever state that they're in, you can export this
to a CSV too and, and just filter it by that by location.
If they don't have multiple locations, then this is kind
of moot, but I'm just giving you everything
that we're doing here for the
type of clients that we're working with.
So, multi-location clients, if you're doing e-commerce,
right, you could do it by product category, right?
Just to show them kind of a distribution of where
that traffic is going and performance.
Why is this important too from a scoping point of view?
Well, because now we know how, like
where we're gonna spend our time in terms
of developing content, right?
Do they need practice area pages in a certain area?
Let me see here. So you can see here,
this one here only at two pages in Canfield,
they should have, you know, at least 10 practice area pages,
car accident, motorcycle accident pages for,
for every location that they have.
So that's important because now I can scope that out.
Now I can start to understand how much content they're going
to need over what time period.
Makes sense. The next page here is a little bit deeper
of like a, we're we're starting
to fold in much more GEO into these proposals as well.
Just having that conversation.
It's work, it's, it's landing very well.
They're all interested in talking about it,
talking about chat, GPT, they all know it's a thing
and they're using it every day too.
So she just links right here to the page that she's auditing
and then she'll go through and
just basically hit these things.
Now again, this is built for attorneys, right?
But this can stand true
for pretty much any local business service page.
Any, any service businesses, you know, key services pages.
This will apply. Again, if you're doing e-commerce,
you're just gonna have to modify this a little bit
to look at what the product page templates or,
or collection pages templates should have.
But essentially it's things like authority, right?
So lemme see if she has, no, she doesn't have it in here.
It looks like it's manual. Or maybe she has it down here.
Yeah. So it looks like she
pulls through some of the stuff here.
Most of it's manual as you can see.
And it's just essentially, again,
like we work in this all the time.
She's just got, this is what you're doing.
Well, this is what needs improvement.
She's got like, I mean she's audited
a million practice area pages.
Now I essentially, I'll just kind of talk you through
what we think are, or what we deem important, right?
So authority, is there like a clear, dedicated author?
Is there case results, legal explanations, external linking
to data sources, stuff like that.
Attorney credentials, you know,
and then just she, things that are lacking, right?
So she's probably got like a checklist on the back end
of like five or six things that she's looking
for in each of these criteria.
You know, do you need this?
Not necessarily, but this is such a large part
of our like, practice area.
Page development is such a large part of our service
because it's kind
of the only important pages on their website
that we like to include this in here.
So this is a page level checklist that we have for a key
page on their website.
You can use the exact same thing.
You're just gonna have to obviously modify this
for whatever, whatever industry that you're working with.
It's into the same thing. Practice area, page.
It's just a bit of a more of a written assessment.
Again, don't wanna write
It, it, feed it to chatha PT feed the profile,
feed the spreadsheet in this document to chatha PT
and just ask it to write it for you.
I believe she does use AI to write it.
She, English is not her first language,
but I, I'm be honest, I've never read these before either.
I don't think they do. This is so much
information and that's kind of what I want.
I just want this to be a fire hose
of like valuable information
and data that they're like,
oh man, these people know what they're doing.
You know, like, I trust you.
Like, I don't really give a s**t.
'cause it looks like you know what you're talking about.
You know, it's like if somebody gave me a 50 page legal
presentation, I'd be like, dude, come on, man.
Like, I get it. You're smart. All right?
Like, how much do you, what's your retainer cost, right?
So that's content. And you know, this is, again,
it's important for scoping information.
It's important for them to understand
where we're gonna focus our time and attention.
And then the last piece here is just
going into link building.
So I hate this slide.
I'm actually taking this out because it's not right,
this is like an audit from White Spark,
you know, I'll leave it in there for you guys.
But essentially what it's looking at,
it looks like she took it outta this one.
Yeah. Yeah. I honestly, I don't, I don't,
I don't like this slide because I've, I can't tell you
how many times that, like, I don't even look at it, right?
But then a, a prospect will be like, wait a second,
we do have a profile on Yelp.
Why does that not say it's happening?
So I'm just gonna delete this for you guys. Sorry.
So instead, oops, excuse me.
What we have here is like a core directory
citation audit that we do.
These are profiles that we deem they must have.
And again, this is stuff
that you guys should have internally for whatever industry
that you're working with, if
you're working with dentists, right?
It's not gonna be, I mean, these are,
these are basic directory ones.
These are applicable for everything.
But then getting into like legal directories, right?
So like, obviously AVO
and fine law, if you're working with dentists
or doctors, that's not the case.
You're just gonna have to determine what these are for you.
But this is important, right?
These, we, we d we deem these as links.
If they don't have these built, they need them, right?
These are very, very important. Uh, just looking at this.
And again, so she has this checklist here.
Let me zoom out a little bit here for, you can see this.
So again, this is used for us,
but essentially all she's doing is she's
just manually searching these.
So it takes a good 10 minutes of research to do this.
You can probably use chat GPT for this too, I believe.
I don't know how accurate it is.
But again, you feed the spreadsheet to ai, you, you say,
this is the, the prospect we're working on,
tell me if they have a profile on these,
it can build it for you, right?
So ways that you can speed this up and save time.
But again, these are important
because this is feeding the scope.
This is looking for more areas of opportunity.
And this is how you build a bigger scope
by finding these things instead
of just, you know, pitching them.
Kind of like a blanket thing, right?
The next slide, very simple link gap analysis.
This is literally just pulling data directly from arus.
Honestly, like I, what I prefer is just looking at this,
but we leave the whole thing in
because all I've really talked to them is, so again,
sorry, reframe this.
You pull this from hres here in the spreadsheet,
back wings profile, website, competitor average,
and then these two, and this is just summing these two up.
So you, dang it,
you just fill out this information directly from Atress.
Very simple. How do you do that? You just come over here.
You guys know how to use atress.
You just grab this information directly from Atress, right?
Again, there's some, there's some formulas in here
that will calculate some of this for you as well.
Now, when I'm pitching this, I'm just gonna close this,
sorry, when I'm pitching this, what I like
to tell them is I like to focus on these two things.
And this is what I'll tell 'em.
I'll say, look, domain ratings a score one out of a hundred,
it basically gives us the equity, authority
and power of the backlinks that you have.
Not an exact science, but it's a very quick litmus test
of your link quality profile, right?
So you can see here, you're in,
you know, your second to stone.
You're a little bit above Jeffrey,
but you're, you're, you're where you need,
and this is important for us too,
because like, how much time and effort do we want us
and money do we wanna spend on link building?
We gotta know this. We gotta be able to scope this out ahead
of time so we can formulate the right amount of links
that we're gonna wanna build for these prospects.
So remember, and then I'll say, look at ignore backlinks,
because every one referring domain could
create a million backlinks.
So I like to look at total referring domains,
and I'll tell them, and people ask about this in blueprint
all the time, like, how do you know how many links to build?
This is how much, right?
Because I'm gonna look and say, okay, it, it's not one
to one, but if we're gonna catch stone here,
you've got about a 350 link discrepancy, right?
Not all links are created equal.
I tell 'em all the time that one link we build is usually
equivalent of three because we're building very high quality
authority authority domains.
So call it a hundred links.
So we'll say, okay, that's a hundred links if we want
to get there over the course of the next year, that's
what, eight links a month.
If my math is right, about eight links a month,
it's very doable, right?
And that's usually how we scope these out in terms of links.
And I'll show you what a proposal
and scope looks like in a second.
And then this is just a very simple summary
that she puts together to wrap it up.
Does that make sense? This is the entire analysis.
You see a live version, you see the template version.
This is just a, a template that you can put on the backend,
you know, about your team.
Any credentials that you have
that you wanna put in here, just add them in.
And again, we have these templates here for you.
So that is the, the analysis template, right?
That's part one. Now, there's two options here, right?
We use a, this is not like a full proposal, right?
This is analysis, there's no, a proposal is proposed work.
So part two of this is doing the analysis
and then also preparing the, the proposal,
AKA, the scope of work.
So I call this the scope of work,
but I'll have this done at the same time
as the analysis done, because I'll present this
to them at the end of the call.
So I'll say, do you have any questions on the analysis?
Go through it. And I'll say, okay, now let's talk about
how we're actually gonna implement this and improve and,
and, and make all these changes, right?
And that's where this comes into play.
So this is another template, right?
And that will usually put in like a very
simple overview here, just custom.
This is gonna be the scope of work.
So sometimes we'll send these that we're doing PPC
and we'll just put PPC in here as well, right?
But this one is an SEO only proposal.
So this one has the local SEO organic,
and this is all templated copy.
And just make a copy
of the previous document and let it ride.
So this is new actually.
She just put this in what you can expect.
And then it gets into the scope of work.
So this is really the proposal.
This is what am I getting and when
and how much does it cost, right?
So the first part, which is the longest
part, is what are we doing?
What do we need work on, you know, areas of opportunity.
Now this is saying, this is how we're actually gonna go in
and, and make the improvements
to hit those, those growth numbers.
So this is ours. Again, you guys have access to it.
Please don't copy it.
Please don't copy it
because one, you're probably not doing all this stuff
because a lot of this is built for lawyers.
And two, if you send this to somebody and I,
and I'm happen to get it,
like you're, you're gonna get eviscerated.
I'm just calling telling you what it is.
'cause this has happened before.
And like that agency that did it got eviscerated by me
because when I'm pitching, I don't play games.
I'm just letting you know, like
I'm coming for everyone's jugular.
I don't care how much blood gets on my shirt.
So change this, please. It's a template.
Use it as a template. It is not a copy and paste thing.
The first piece for this is tracking and analytics.
So this is everything that we do just in the scope of that.
And you can kind of read through this stuff.
And then I'd like to link to an example as well here too,
just so people can, can, can feel what we're doing.
So I'll link to like a report that we have, tech,
SE and website management.
These are all like the,
the high level things that we're doing here.
Some examples of documents that, again, deliverables,
local SEO optimizations, the scope of work that we're doing
for local SEO, everything that's included inside of there.
This is new for us. We're actually, uh, starting
to do review generation, which is like review automations.
I actually just added this in like two hours ago.
So this is brand new. And it's obviously, we talk about,
I talk about reviews, like in that analysis document.
Like one of the biggest things I'm talking about throughout
this process and we're doing the local SEO part
is reviews, right?
Like, again, very easy for them
to be like, damn, we only have three 40.
It's just like links. They have 900.
It's like, that is almost a one-to-one.
You need more reviews. So we're starting to roll that out.
I'll keep you guys posted on how that goes.
But essentially a, a review automation system,
content creation, how many words we're gonna do per month.
That's how we scope it out, right?
So this client, 12,000 words a month, that's about,
you know, five to six pages, maybe less, four
to six pages depending on what type of page, the type
of content that we're doing, the deliverables
that they're getting within that,
and everything that we're doing.
Full, full content management,
some examples of content that we've written.
Then it goes into link building and it talks about the type
of links that we're gonna get and the type
of links that we're gonna build for them.
And then it, this is new as well. It's just like GEO stuff.
Very basic boilerplate stuff, right?
A lot of it is already kind of like within the scope of SEO,
but we're just re-putting it in here
just to make it seem more.
And then we get into pricing and timelines.
So again, what am I getting and when am I getting it?
Now you have the answer to that. And how much does it cost?
This is the quote that we put together.
And again, you guys have access to this.
Now you can just arrange this,
but you can see now this is a very complete,
and then this is like the agreement portion.
We do monthly, monthly contracts.
So it just has this language in here.
If they want to put an initial on this, they're fine,
but like, we don't need to.
They have everything they need
now to make a decision, right?
So again, analysis we go through, I walk you through
how I build it and how I pitch that.
You're gonna be able to watch live calls
underneath this if you're in school right now.
And then make sure that you put
this document together with it.
So after you get the analysis, you say, okay,
now we talked about what needs to be done,
let's talk about how, right?
And let's talk about what we're gonna do, exactly
what you're gonna get, when you're gonna get it,
and how much it's gonna cost, right?
Very clear, very straightforward, very difficult for them
to, don't say wriggle out of it,
but like, you know, they have everything they need
to make a decision that's
important while we're doing this, right?
They need to
Have everything in front of 'em so they can, you know,
make a decision about what they're gonna do.
So I do encourage you guys to take that proposal
as homework, that analysis, make a copy of it,
and start the rebranding process.
Look at what's included, customize it to your industry.
Again, this stuff obviously slants a little bit more towards
legal than it does for home services,
but we do have home services client.
We use the exact same proposal. It's the same thing.
You just gotta customize a little bit.